Victor Matthews

🗣 Denver, Colorado 🛮 victormmatthews@gmail.com 🗖 (616) 970 0690 🔚 in/victor-matthews-x 🕳 victormmatthews.me

SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the aviation and aerospace industry as well as supply chain management of the food & beverages industry. Skilled in Python, Java, Angular, and SQL. Strong engineering professional, graduated from Ferris State University.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Boeing | Aviation Data Solutions

May 2021 - Present, Englewood, CO (Remote)

- · Created a workflow in DataBricks for aeronautical data extraction, resulting in over 100x faster data delivery to customers.
- · Led development of Angular UI's to configure aeronautical data needs for airline and business customers around the world.
- Drove the daily execution of product development in a fast paced agile environment. Involved in the entire software development life cycle, from idea creation and development, all the way through to maintenance and support of the delivered system.
- Decomposed complex requirements and capabilities into executable discrete user stories, using Python to develop backend's and Angular to develop UI's with integration, testing, and delivery in a CI/CD pipeline.

Software Engineer

Gordon Food Service | IT Warehouse Team

March 2016 - May 2021, Grand Rapids, MI

- · Working with the IT Warehouse team, helped develop and support the warehouse management system.
- · Subject matter expert on Inventory Control and Material Handling Control Systems.
- · Created and deployed a new Angular app, replacing the old telnet devices in the warehouses.
- · Updated and revamped software used throughout the warehouse for receiving, selection, inventory control, and shipping.

Asset Administrator

Gordon Food Service | North American Asset Management Team

May 2015 - March 2016, Grand Rapids, MI

- · Automated the internal IT hardware & software PO request system using JavaScript, resulting in faster throughput for PO requests.
- · Implemented field validation for forms to ensure the user entered all the information needed, based on the specific users requests.
- · Awarded the Gordon Food Service J&P Cup award, a yearly award given to one of the IT teams.

PROJECTS

Communication Leader

Lakewood Fermentation Club · lakewoodfermentation.club · December 2023 - Present

- Built an Angular app to manage and send out text messages to club members for events and newsletters. Using AWS, host the app with Amplify, secure login with Cognito, manage members with DynamoDB, send messages with Lambda through a Twilio integration.
- \cdot Maintain the clubs website, write monthly newsletters, handle communication through email and text to club members.
- · Apart of the clubs leadership team, setup and run monthly meetings, quarterly challenges, and other club events.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science | Digital Media Software Engineering

Ferris State University · Grand Rapids, MI · 2017

SKILLS

Back End: Python, Java, SQL, C#

Front End: Angular 2+, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Misc: Git, DataBricks, Docker, Azure, AWS